Kung Fu Panda Holiday is a animation, family, tv
movie film directed by Tim Johnson.
The Winter Feast is Po's favorite holiday.
Every year he and his father hang decorations, cook
together, and serve noodle soup to the villagers.
But this year Shifu informs Po that as Dragon Warrior, it is his duty
to host the formal Winter Feast at the Jade Palace.
Po is caught between his obligations as the Dragon Warrior and
his family traditions: between Shifu and Mr.
Po (voice), played by Jack Black.
Shifu (voice), played by Dustin Hoffman.
Tigress (voice), played by Angelina Jolie.
Mantis (voice), played by Seth Rogen.
Viper (voice), played by Lucy Liu.
Crane (voice), played by David Cross.
Kung Fu Panda is a 2008 American animated martial arts comedy film directed by John Stevenson and Mark Osborne
and written by Jonathan Aibel and Glenn Berger from a story by Ethan Reiff and Cyrus Voris.
Produced by DreamWorks Animation, it is the first
installment in the Kung Fu Panda franchise.
Starring Jack Black as the voice of the titular character, the film, set in a version of ancient China populated by
anthropomorphic animals, centers on a bumbling giant panda named Po, a kung fu enthusiast living in the Valley of Peace.
When the savage snow leopard Tai Lung is foretold to escape imprisonment and attack the Valley, Po is unwittingly named the "Dragon
Warrior", a prophesied hero worthy of reading a scroll that has been intended to grant its reader limitless power.
The film began development in October 2004, and was initially
conceived as a parody of martial arts films.
However, director Stevenson decided instead to make an action-comedy wuxia film that
incorporated the hero's journey narrative for the lead character.
The project was announced in September 2005.
As with most DreamWorks Animation films, the score for Kung Fu Panda was composed
by Hans Zimmer, on this occasion collaborating with John Powell.
Zimmer visited China to absorb the culture, and used the China
National Symphony Orchestra as part of the scoring process.
Kung Fu Panda premiered at the 2008 Cannes Film Festival on May 15, 2008, and was
theatrically released in the United States on June 6 by Paramount Pictures.
It grossed $632 million on a budget of $130 million, making it the third highest
grossing film of 2008 and the highest-grossing animated film of the year.
It received positive reviews from critics, and was nominated for Best Animated
Feature at the Academy Awards, and the Golden Globe Awards.
The film's success spawned a franchise including three sequels;
the first, Kung Fu Panda 2, was released in 2011.
The film explores themes of martial arts, kung fu, holiday, cooking, restaurant.
The tone is lighthearted.